<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://meyert11.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://meyert11.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-03-31T12:56:44+00:00</updated><id>https://meyert11.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Travis Meyer&apos;s Website. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Add Experimental Models to your Open Webui</title><link href="https://meyert11.github.io/data-science/ai/2025/03/29/OpenWebuiPlusAPI.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Add Experimental Models to your Open Webui"/><published>2025-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://meyert11.github.io/data-science/ai/2025/03/29/OpenWebuiPlusAPI</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://meyert11.github.io/data-science/ai/2025/03/29/OpenWebuiPlusAPI.html"><![CDATA[<p>Kind of working backwards, as I setup the site, but I currently have an Open Webui hosted in my basement rig, where 2 rtx 3080s can run a bunch of modern models in a secure, private network. Google’s new model, Gemini 2.5 experimental is getting a lot of hype so I thought - wouldn’t it be nice if I could connect Open WebUI to the Google API, so on my phone, tablet or computers I can utilize the latest models… well it turns out it’s super easy!</p> <p>First - get your free API from google’s AI Studio https://aistudio.google.com/apikey</p> <h2 id="ais-suggestion">AI’s suggestion</h2> <p>The first thing I did was search perplexity for a solution. It had me creating a litellm container, but the ports started to conflict with open-webui’s ports. There were some work arounds, but I thought let’s just give it a try manually. So I asked it if I already had an API key, can i connect to Google’s api in open webui, and it gave ‘almost’ the right answer.</p> <h2 id="configuring-direct-connections">Configuring Direct Connections</h2> <p>Open WebUI version: 0.5.20 There’s a major disconnect between AI models and some of the github software, and open webui is a prime example. It will tell me how to traverse the admin panel and settings and sections just won’t exist. For example it told me to go to Admin panel, connections and add a direct connection, however this area just had a toggle switch, nothing else.</p> <p>So after exploring on my own, I found the solution:</p> <ol> <li> <p>After logging into to your user account, click on your icon in the upper right, then settings (not admin panel)</p> </li> <li> <p>Click Connections, then the plus botton to add a new connection</p> </li> <li> <p>For Google models, put this for the URL: https://generativelanguage.googleapis.com/v1beta</p> </li> <li> <p>Then add your API key in the ‘Key’ section</p> </li> </ol> <p>The next step is critical, you HAVE to add the Model ID, and only 1 model will show up for each connection, so don’t add more, only the top one works.</p> <ol> <li>Click the Add a model ID plus sign, and type in exactly the model ID: eg gemini-2.5-pro-exp-03-25</li> </ol> <p>Dont’ worry about errors if you click ‘verify connection’ mine had errors too, but it still works.</p> <ol> <li>Click Save, Save, then go back to New Chat and under models you’ll see your model. if you don’t see the model, try searching for it. Enjoy!!</li> </ol> <p>Eventually I’ll create a blog about creating the local Open WebUI in a proxmox environment, and give the updates for the new WebUI.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="data-science"/><category term="AI"/><category term="AI"/><category term="Gemini"/><category term="machine-learning"/><category term="local-models"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Make your local Open Webui even better by connecting it to free experimental models by Google/Facebook/OpenAI]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bridging the Gap From Neuroscience to Data Science</title><link href="https://meyert11.github.io/data-science/neuroscience/career-transition/2025/03/26/Welcome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bridging the Gap From Neuroscience to Data Science"/><published>2025-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://meyert11.github.io/data-science/neuroscience/career-transition/2025/03/26/Welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://meyert11.github.io/data-science/neuroscience/career-transition/2025/03/26/Welcome.html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my blog! As someone who has spent years immersed in the world of neuroscience research—first at Carnegie Mellon and later at the University of Pennsylvania—I recently embarked on an exciting new chapter in my career: transitioning to a Senior Data Scientist role at Vanguard. This blog is my space to share insights, lessons learned, and reflections on this journey, as well as to explore topics that inspire me in both science and data.</p> <h2 id="why-the-shift">Why the Shift?</h2> <p>At first glance, neuroscience and data science might seem worlds apart. However, they share a common thread: the pursuit of understanding complex systems. In neuroscience, I studied how neural networks process information; in data science, I analyze patterns in data to solve real-world problems. The tools and techniques I once used to decode the brain—statistical modeling, machine learning, and data visualization—are now helping me tackle challenges in finance.</p> <h2 id="lessons-from-neuroscience-that-shape-my-data-science-work">Lessons from Neuroscience That Shape My Data Science Work</h2> <ol> <li> <p><strong>The Power of Asking the Right Questions</strong><br/> In research, formulating a clear hypothesis is half the battle. Similarly, in data science, defining the problem is critical. My academic training taught me to approach problems methodically, ensuring that every analysis starts with a strong foundation.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Interdisciplinary Thinking</strong><br/> Neuroscience thrives at the intersection of biology, psychology, and computation. This interdisciplinary mindset has been invaluable in data science, where collaboration across domains often leads to innovative solutions.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Storytelling with Data</strong><br/> Whether presenting research findings or crafting financial insights, storytelling is key. Communicating complex ideas clearly and effectively is a skill I honed during my academic career and continue to refine in my current role.</p> </li> </ol> <h2 id="whats-next-for-this-blog">What’s Next for This Blog?</h2> <p>Through this blog, I hope to explore topics that sit at the crossroads of science and data. Here are a few ideas for future posts:</p> <ul> <li>Practical tips for transitioning from academia to industry.</li> <li>How neuroscience principles can inform data science practices (and vice versa).</li> <li>Tutorials on machine learning techniques or tools I’ve found useful.</li> <li>Reflections on personal growth and career development.</li> </ul> <p>I also plan to write about ongoing projects—both professional and personal—and share resources that have been instrumental in my journey. If you’re interested in neuroscience, data science, or career transitions (or all three!), I’d love for you to join me on this adventure.</p> <h2 id="lets-connect">Let’s Connect</h2> <p>If you’ve navigated a similar career path or are curious about any aspect of my work, feel free to reach out at travismeyerphd @ gmail.com or via [LinkedIn]www.linkedin.com/in/travis-meyer-4b3b2315. I’m always eager to exchange ideas and learn from others.</p> <p>Thanks for reading—I’m excited to see where this blogging journey takes us!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="data-science"/><category term="neuroscience"/><category term="career-transition"/><category term="academia"/><category term="industry"/><category term="machine-learning"/><category term="Vanguard"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to my blog! As someone who has spent years immersed in the world of neuroscience research—first at Carnegie Mellon and later at the University of Pennsylvania—I recently embarked on an exciting new chapter in my career: transitioning to a Senior Data Scientist role at Vanguard. This blog is my space to share insights, lessons learned, and reflections on this journey, as well as to explore topics that inspire me in both science and data.]]></summary></entry></feed>